Register of the Walter Henry Judd papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- CONGRESSIONAL FILE, 1924-1983 (Box 61-156)
  - General
    - Trips
      - United States Information Service (USIS) - 1947 September-October, 1947-1948
        - Czechoslovakia, 1947 (Box-folder 79: 15)
          Transcripts of news articles, meeting summaries, questionnaire, itinerary, and a report.
        - Denmark, 1947 (Box-folder 79: 16)
          Letters, notes, report, and miscellany.
        - England, 1947 (Box-folder 79: 17)
          Notes, memorandum, itinerary, and a report.
        - Finland, 1947 (Box-folder 79: 18)
          Meeting summary, report, and miscellany.
        - France and Luxembourg, 1947 (Box-folder 79: 19)
          Fact sheets, reports, notes, and meeting summaries.
        - Germany, 1947 (Box-folder 79: 20)
          Meeting summary, reports, miscellany, itinerary, and memoranda.
        - Greece, 1947 (Box-folder 80: 1)
          Itinerary, letters, meeting summaries, reports, clippings, and a press release.
        - Hungary, 1947 (Box-folder 80: 2)
          Itinerary, reports, and notes.
        - Italy, 1947 (Box-folder 80: 3)
          Itinerary, meeting summary, letter, and reports.
        - Netherlands, 1947 (Box-folder 80: 4)
          Meeting summary, memorandum, itinerary, press release, and miscellany.
        - Norway, 1947 (Box-folder 80: 5)
          Itinerary, notes, letter, meeting summaries, and clippings.
        - Poland, 1947 (Box-folder 80: 6)
          Itinerary, meeting summaries, reports, and a memorandum.
        - Portugal, 1947 (Box-folder 80: 7)
          Itinerary, reports, and miscellany.
        - Rumania, 1947 (Box-folder 80: 8)
          Invitation, letters, reports, and a news article.
        - Spain, 1947-1948 (Box-folder 80: 9)
          Clippings, miscellany, reports, meeting summaries (including General Franco), and letters.
        - Sweden, 1947 (Box-folder 80: 10)
          Itinerary, pamphlet, meeting summary, notes, memorandum, reports, and miscellany.
        - Turkey, 1947 (Box-folder 80: 11)
          Itinerary, news articles, miscellany, memorandum, reports, and a telegram.
      - Far East - 1947 October-November, 1946-1948
        - General, 1947 (Box-folder 80: 12)
          Notes, itineraries, and correspondence.
        - China
          - General, 1947-1948 (Box-folder 80: 13)
            State Department reports, wire reports and news articles, clippings, letter, and miscellany.
          - Nanking and Peiping, 1947 (Box-folder 80: 14)
            Lists, tables, memoranda, reports, correspondence, notes, press release, pamphlet, and miscellany.
          - Shanghai, 1947 (Box-folder 81: 1)
            Notes, itinerary, memoranda, bulletin, news articles, and miscellany.
        - Japan, 1947 (Box-folder 81: 2)
          Statements, press release, reports, itinerary, and miscellany.
        - Korea, 1946-1948 (Box-folder 81: 3)
          Correspondence, memoranda, speech, reports, newsletter, printed articles, clippings, press release, and miscellany.
      - World Health Organization (WHO) Assembly, Geneva, 1950 (Box-folder 81: 4)
        Clippings, correspondence, notes, statements, reports, miscellany, minutes, and press releases.
      - 1951
        - European reconstruction (Marshall Plan and military aid programs) study group, June (Box-folder 81: 5)
          Correspondence (including Dwight Eisenhower), newsletter, notes on a meeting with General Eisenhower, itineraries, clipping, statement, notes, and miscellany.
        - Council of Europe meeting, Strasbourg - 1951 November, 1947-1953
          - General, 1947-1953 (Box-folder 81: 6)
            Reports, pamphlets, bulletin, correspondence, clippings, miscellany and press releases.
          - Conference material, 1951 (Box-folder 81: 7, Box-folder 82: 1)
            Notes, reports, statistics, miscellany, resolutions, debate transcripts, speeches, and a letter.
      - India, Pakistan and the Far East, 1953 April (Box-folder 82: 2)
        Clippings, correspondence, reports, newsletters, statement, notes, miscellany and itineraries.
      - Far East - 1953 November, 1950-1954
        - General, 1953-1954 (Box-folder 82: 3-5)
          Correspondence (including General Matthew Ridgway and Congressional colleagues), memorandum, itineraries, clippings, press release, miscellany, and a report.
        - Burma, 1953-1954 (Box-folder 83: 1)
          Clipping, budget, meeting memorandum, miscellany, and correspondence.
        - Hong Kong, 1950-1954 (Box-folder 83: 2)
          Correspondence and statements.
        - Indonesia, 1953-1954 (Box-folder 83: 3)
          Correspondence, memorandum, and miscellany.
        - Japan, 1953-1954 (Box-folder 83: 4)
          Miscellany and correspondence.
        - Korea, 1953-1954 (Box-folder 83: 5)
          Correspondence (including Syngman Rhee), clipping, notes, and miscellany.
        - Laos, 1953-1954 (Box-folder 83: 6)
          Letter and miscellany.
        - Malaysia, 1952-1954 (Box-folder 83: 7)
        - Philippines, 1953-1954 (Box-folder 83: 8)
        - Taiwan, 1951-1954 (Box-folder 83: 9)
          Clippings, miscellany, correspondence, memorandum, map, and a pamphlet.
        - Thailand, 1953-1954 (Box-folder 83: 10)
          Correspondence and miscellany. Includes a letter relating to conditions in Cambodia.
        - Vietnam, 1953-1954 (Box-folder 83: 11)
      - Middle and Far East - 1955 October-December, 1955-1957
        - General, 1955-1957 (Box-folder 83: 12-13)
          Extensive travel notes and reports, itinerary, miscellany, a press release, and correspondence.
        - Afghanistan, 1955 (Box-folder 84: 1)
          Itinerary.
        - Burma, 1955 (Box-folder 84: 2)
        - Cambodia, 1955 (Box-folder 84: 3)
        - Ceylon, 1955 (Box-folder 84: 4)
        - Egypt, 1955 (Box-folder 84: 5)
          Pamphlet and report with cover letter.
        - Hong Kong, 1955 (Box-folder 84: 6)
          Itinerary and miscellany.
        - India, 1955 (Box-folder 84: 7)
        - Indonesia, 1956 (Box-folder 84: 8)
          Invitation.
        - Iran, 1955 (Box-folder 84: 9)
          Briefing materials relating to the U.S. military mission in Iran and miscellany.
        - Iraq, 1955 (Box-folder 84: 10)
          Report, briefing materials, and miscellany.
        - Israel, 1955 (Box-folder 84: 11)
          Miscellany.
        - Italy, 1955 (Box-folder 84: 12)
        - Japan, 1955 (Box-folder 84: 13)
          Clippings, correspondence, and miscellany.
        - Korea, 1955 (Box-folder 84: 14)
          Correspondence, miscellany, and clippings.
        - Lebanon, 1955 (Box-folder 84: 15)
        - Pakistan, 1955 (Box-folder 84: 16)
          Letter and itinerary.
        - Philippines, 1955 (Box-folder 84: 17)
          Notes and itinerary.
        - Syria, 1955 (Box-folder 84: 18)
        - Taiwan, 1955 (Box-folder 84: 19)
          Correspondence, clippings, serial issue, and miscellany.
        - Thailand, 1955 (Box-folder 84: 20)
        - Turkey, 1955 (Box-folder 84: 21)
        - Vietnam, 1955 (Box-folder 84: 22)
      - Delegation to the 1956 inauguration of President Syngman Rhee of Korea, 1953-1958 (Box-folder 84: 23)
        Correspondence (including John Foster Dulles), miscellany, schedules, notes, speech (Syngman Rhee), memorandum, and a clipping.
      - Middle and Far East - 1959, 1957-1960
        - General, 1959-1960 (Box-folder 84: 24-26)
          Correspondence, miscellany, a press report, State Department briefing material (relating to general conditions and development projects in multiple countries), reports, and draft of Judd minority views.
        - Afghanistan, 1959 (Box-folder 85: 1)
          Letter and pamphlets.
        - Cambodia, 1959 (Box-folder 85: 2)
          Pamphlet, miscellany, speech draft, telegrams, and charts.
        - Hong Kong, 1958-1959 (Box-folder 85: 3)
          Correspondence, clippings, miscellany, pamphlet, Chinese language publications, memoranda, and reports. Primarily relates to Chinese refugees and USIS programs.
        - Indonesia, 1958-1959 (Box-folder 85: 4)
          Pamphlets, miscellany, briefing materials, map, letter, and biographical sketches.
        - India, 1959 (Box-folder 85: 5)
          Correspondence (including Ambassador Ellsworth Bunker), clipping, and miscellany.
        - Iran, 1957-1959 (Box-folder 85: 6)
          Report, maps, and briefing materials relating to the U.S. military mission in Iran.
        - Japan, 1959 (Box-folder 85: 7)
          Briefing material prepared by the U.S. High Commissioner of the Ryukyu Islands.
        - Korea, 1959 (Box-folder 85: 8)
          Correspondence, reports, summary of a meeting with Syngman Rhee, clippings, and miscellany.
        - Laos, 1959 (Box-folder 85: 9)
          Correspondence, report, and miscellany.
        - Pakistan, 1959-1960 (Box-folder 85: 10)
          Reports, pamphlets, letter, and miscellany.
        - Philippines, 1959-1961 (Box-folder 85: 11)
          Correspondence, speech, photographs, and miscellany.
        - Taiwan, 1958-1959 (Box-folder 86: 1)
          Pamphlets, correspondence, reports, and miscellany.
        - Thailand, 1959 (Box-folder 86: 2)
          Correspondence, itinerary, and a clipping.
        - Vietnam, 1958-1960 (Box-folder 86: 3)
          Correspondence (Elbridge Durbrow), clippings, reports, and miscellany.
      - Relating to U.S. aid programs - 1961, 1960-1962
        - General, 1961 (Box-folder 86: 4)
          Itinerary and press release.
        - Afghanistan, 1961 (Box-folder 86: 5)
          Letter.
        - Hong Kong, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 86: 6)
          Reports, correspondence, clipping, and miscellany.
        - India, 1961 (Box-folder 86: 7)
          Correspondence, reports, press release, booklet, charts, notes, and miscellany.
        - Iran, 1961 (Box-folder 86: 8)
          Report, correspondence, and an itinerary.
        - Japan, 1961 (Box-folder 86: 9)
        - Korea, 1960-1961 (Box-folder 86: 10)
          Report, clippings, press release, diagrams, correspondence, bulletin, and itinerary.
        - Pakistan, 1961 (Box-folder 86: 11)
          Correspondence, serial issue, reports, press releases, and miscellany.
        - Taiwan, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 86: 12)
          Correspondence, clippings, pamphlets, Chinese Communist leaflets, Nationalist "psychological warfare" material, booklet, reports, and miscellany. Includes information on refugee Chinese.
        - Thailand, 1960-1961 (Box-folder 87: 1)
          Correspondence, reports, clippings, and miscellany.
        - Turkey, 1961 (Box-folder 87: 2)
          Report, letter, memorandum, and miscellany.
        - Vietnam, 1961 (Box-folder 87: 3)
          Pamphlet, letters, and miscellany.
      - U.S.-British Parliamentarians meeting, Bermuda - 1962, 1960-1962 (Box-folder 87: 4)
        Correspondence, notes, biographical sketches, agenda, and miscellany.
    - Voting records, 1953-1962 (Box-folder 87: 5-6)
      Printed matter, correspondence, and notes.
    - Executive departments
      - General
        - Correspondence, 1945-1965 (Box-folder 90: 1-4, Box 88-89, Box-folder 87: 7)
          Primarily relates to independent and miscellaneous government agencies, including the National Labor Relations Board, the Veterans Administration, the Post Office Department, the Federal Communications Commission, the Civil Service Commission, the General Accounting Office, the National Housing Agency, the Tariff Commission, the Maritime Commission, and the Federal Trade Commission.
        - Emergency agencies
          - General correspondence, 1945-1955 (Box-folder 90: 5)
            Primarily relates to World War II agencies, including the War Manpower Commission, the Solid Fuels Administration, the Office of War Information, the War Shipping Administration, the War Labor Board, the Office of Defense Mobilization, and the Economic Stabilization Agency.
          - Office of Defense Transportation, 1945 (Box-folder 90: 6)
          - Office of Price Administration, 1945-1947 (Box-folder 91: 1-3)
          - Office of Price Stabilization, 1950-1953 (Box-folder 91: 4)
          - Wage Stabilization Board, 1950-1952 (Box-folder 91: 5)
          - War Assets Administration, 1945-1946 (Box-folder 91: 6)
          - War Production Board/Civilian Production Board, 1945-1946 (Box-folder 91: 7)
        - White House, 1945-1969 (Box-folder 91: 8-9)
          General and official correspondence. Includes material relating to presidential administrations and letters to Lawrence O'Brien, George McGovern, Walt Rostow, and McGeorge Bundy.
      - Agriculture Department
        - Correspondence, 1945-1963 (Box-folder 92: 1-4)
          General and official correspondence. Includes material relating to food shortages, surpluses, price supports, schools lunches, wilderness areas, the Commodity Credit Corporation, and Secretary Ezra T. Benson, and correspondence with Orville Freeman.
        - Benson, Ezra Taft, 1954-1958 (Box-folder 92: 5)
          Correspondence, notes (including a meeting with Secretary Benson), statements (Ezra Benson), a report on surplus grain, and clippings relating to Dr. Judd's criticism of Secretary Benson's policy.
        - Ladejinsky, Wolf, 1954-1960 (Box-folder 92: 6)
          Correspondence (including Walter Robertson, J. Graham Parsons, and Ezra T. Benson), clippings, notes, printed article, statements (including Harold Stassen), and a report on Vietnam. Relates to the dismissal of Wolf Ladejinsky on loyalty-security grounds and includes material relating to his subsequent work for the ICA in Asia.
        - War Food Administration, 1945 (Box-folder 92: 7)
          Correspondence.
      - Commerce Department
        - Correspondence, 1945-1969 (Box-folder 93: 1-2, Box-folder 92: 8)
          General and official correspondence. Includes material relating to patents, surplus property, waterways, highways, the census, Northwest Airlines, the Civil Aeronautics Authority, and the appointment of Henry Wallace as Secretary, and correspondence with Maurice Stans and Luther Hodges.
        - 1960 census, 1959-1960 (Box-folder 93: 3)
          Correspondence, clippings, regulations, forms, and miscellany.
      - Defense Department, 1945-1970 (Box 94-95, Box-folder 96: 1, Box-folder 93: 4-6)
        Includes the former Navy and War Departments. General and official correspondence. Includes material relating to prisoners of war, military service, discharges, selective service, the Army Corps of Engineers, and military facilities, and correspondence with Robert McNamara.
      - Health, Education, and Welfare Department, 1945-1962 (Box-folder 96: 2-5)
        Includes the former Federal Security Agency. General and official correspondence. Includes material relating to social security, the Public Health Service, food and drug regulations, and the fluoridation of water, and correspondence with Abraham Ribicoff.
      - Interior Department, 1945-1976 (Box-folder 96: 6-7)
        General and official correspondence. Includes material relating to the War Relocation Authority, the Bureau of Indian Affairs, fish and wildlife, mineral resources, power projects, and the National Park Service, and correspondence with Stewart Udall.
      - Justice Department, 1945-1964 (Box-folder 96: 8, Box-folder 97: 1-2)
        General and official correspondence. Includes material relating to the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the Immigration and Naturalization Service, criminal procedure, Alger Hiss, and Julius and Ethel Rosenberg, and correspondence with J. Edgar Hoover and Robert Kennedy, as well as printed material relating to statements by Dr. Judd about the Walter Jenkins case.
      - Labor Department, 1945-1962 (Box-folder 97: 3-4)
        General and official correspondence. Includes material relating to strikes, compensation, and unemployment, and correspondence with Arthur Goldberg.
      - State Department
        Material relating to specific issues is filed under the appropriate subject category.
        - General, 1948-1960 (Box-folder 97: 5)
          Reports, statements (including Dean Rusk, Christian Herter, John Foster Dulles, and Robert Murphy), printed articles, pamphlets, bulletin, press releases, minutes, clippings, memoranda, notes, and program summaries.
        - Correspondence, 1943-1983 (Box-folder 97: 6-8)
          General and official correspondence. Includes correspondence with George Shultz, Dean Rusk, and William Rogers.
        - Foreign policy and department administration, 1945-1962 (Box-folder 98: 1)
          Correspondence (including Estes Kefauver and George Kennan), speeches, report, notes, radio transcript, newsletter, and clippings. Includes material relating to loyalty-security issues, Alger Hiss, and Harry D. White. Material on China policy is located in the CHINA file.
        - International Cooperation Administration, 1954-1961 (Box-folder 98: 2)
          Reports and correspondence (including Raymond Moyer).
        - International information and educational exchange programs
          - General, 1944-1961 (Box-folder 98: 3)
            Draft and final legislation, speech transcript, reports, notes, press releases, program summaries, and budgets. Includes material relating to the United States Information Service, the United States Information Agency, and the International Information Adminstration.
          - Correspondence, 1944-1969 (Box-folder 99: 1, Box-folder 98: 4-6)
            Includes general (primarily applicants for educational exchange programs), United States Information Agency (including Edward R. Murrow; see also: Trips), and official (including Franklin Roosevelt, Elbridge Durbrow, and other government officials) correspondence.
          - Aid to Chinese and Korean students, 1947-1955 (Box-folder 99: 2)
            Correspondence and reports.
          - Voice of America, 1948-1960 (Box-folder 99: 3)
            Correspondence and a press release.
        - Passports and visas, 1945-1962. (Box-folder 99: 4-6)
          Correspondence. See also: Immigration.
        - Personnel, 1949-1960 (Box-folder 100: 1)
          Correspondence and a memorandum. Relates to inquiries, department employees, and policies.
        - Prisoners and displaced persons, 1950-1961 (Box-folder 100: 2)
          Correspondence. See also: CHINA FILE/Prisoners.
      - Treasury Department, 1943-1969 (Box-folder 100: 3-5)
        General and official correspondence. Includes material relating to the Bretton Woods conference, the Internal Revenue Service, and customs regulations.
    - Former Members of Congress
      - General
        - Administrative material, notes, proposed legislation, by-laws, lists, resolution, and organizational charts, 1969-circa 1982 (Box-folder 100: 6)
        - Newsletters, clippings and press releases, 1971-1982 (Box-folder 100: 7)
        - Correspondence (including Ronald Reagan), general mailings, and memoranda, 1970-1983 (Box-folder 100: 8)
        - Budgets, correspondence, lists, financial statements, and reports, 1970-1983 (Box-folder 100: 9)
        - Meeting materials, 1970-1983 (Box-folder 101: 1-4)
          Includes general agenda, minutes, correspondence, and miscellany for annual and other meetings, including Congressional receptions; Board of Directors agenda, minutes, and miscellany; and Executive Committee agenda and minutes.
        - Membership material, 1970-1981 (Box-folder 101: 5)
          Lists, correspondence, and miscellany.
        - Newsletters, 1974-1983 (Box-folder 101: 6)
        - Reports and memoranda, 1975-1982 (Box-folder 101: 7)
      - Congressional relations, 1963-1983 (Box-folder 102: 1)
        Speeches, legislative proposals, report, and lists.
      - Projects
        - General, 1976-1983 (Box-folder 102: 2)
        - Campus Fellows program, 1970-1983 (Box-folder 102: 3)
          Correspondence, lists, itineraries, and clippings.
        - Oral History program, 1971-1982 (Box-folder 102: 4)
          Clipping, report, and correspondence.
    - House of Representatives
      Correspondence relating to specific issues and legislative proposals can be found following CONGRESSIONAL FILE/General.
      - General, 1945-1962 (Box-folder 102: 5)
        Primarily correspondence. Includes material relating to taxation, lobbying, ethical conduct, government reorganization, joint, special, and investigative committees.
      - Agriculture Committee, 1944-1971 (Box-folder 102: 6-7)
        Correspondence. Includes material relating to school lunch programs, food regulations, government lands, price supports, treatment of animals, and miscellaneous legislation.
      - Appropriations Committee, 1945-1962 (Box-folder 103: 1-3)
        Correspondence. Includes material relating to government departments and programs, construction, and reclamation projects.
      - Armed Services Committee, 1945-1962 (Box-folder 104: 1-3, Box-folder 103: 4-5)
        Includes the former Committees on Military Affairs and Naval Affairs. Correspondence. Includes material relating to selective service, atomic energy, reservists, and Defense Department reorganization.
      - Atomic Energy Committee, 1947-1961 (Box-folder 104: 4)
        Correspondence. Includes material relating to the Atomic Energy Commission, disarmament, and food preservation.
      - Banking and Currency Committee, 1945-1962 (Box-folder 104: 5, Box-folder 105: 1-3)
        Correspondence. Includes material relating to post-World War II loans to Britain, wage and price regulation, housing and rent control, and financial institutions.
      - Claims Committee, 1945-1946 (Box-folder 105: 4)
        Correspondence relating to World War II claims.
      - District of Columbia Committee, 1945-1962 (Box-folder 105: 5)
        Correspondence. Includes material relating to home rule and anti-vivisection.
      - Education and Labor Committee, 1945-1962 (Box-folder 107: 1-3, Box-folder 106: 1-5)
        Correspondence. Includes material relating to labor policy, anti-discrimination, the Taft-Hartley and Landrum-Griffin bills, federal aid to education, minimum wage, and vocational training.
      - Foreign Affairs Committee
        - General, 1947-1962 (Box-folder 107: 4)
          Draft and final copies of legislation, notes, reports, resolutions, statements (including Dwight Eisenhower), press releases, printed matter, and hearing transcripts. Primarily relates to trips and miscellaneous legislation.
        - Correspondence, 1945-1962 (Box-folder 109: 1-3, Box-folder 108: 1-4)
          General and internal. Includes comments on general foreign policy, communism, and miscellaneous specific issues, as well as memoranda.
      - Government Operations Committee
        Includes the former Committee on Executive Department Expenditures.
        - General, 1946-1948 (Box-folder 109: 4)
          Reports, correspondence, notes, memorandum, meeting report, and miscellany.
        - Government corporations, 1945-1946 (Box-folder 109: 5)
          Correspondence, report, statements, and draft and final copies of legislation. Includes material relating to the Reconstruction Finance Corporation.
        - Government reorganization, 1945-1947 (Box-folder 109: 6-7)
          Correspondence, reports, notes, hearing transcripts, statement (Harry S. Truman), resolution, clipping, and meeting reports.
        - State Department personnel, 1947-1948 (Box-folder 110: 1)
          Notes, clipping, correspondence, reports, charts, budgets, and personnel lists. Includes material relating to subversives.
        - Surplus property, 1944-1948 (Box-folder 110: 2)
          Correspondence, press release, resolutions, charts, report, draft and final copies of legislation, meeting summary, and notes.
        - Employment bill and government reorganization (the Hoover Commission), 1945-1962 (Box-folder 110: 3-4)